Hi Michael.
&gt;&gt; Hey Charles, how's it going?
&gt;&gt; It's going quite well,
how's it going with you?
&gt;&gt; Good.
Good.
&gt;&gt; Good Good.
So, today I thought we would talk
a little bit about the philosophy of
Machine Learning.
&gt;&gt; Oh, I hate philosophy.
&gt;&gt; I don't like it much either,
although I am a doctor of philosophy.
&gt;&gt; Oh, that's very impressive.
&gt;&gt; Aren't you a doctor
of philosophy too?
&gt;&gt; I am, it's kind of impressive.
&gt;&gt; It is kind of impressive.
So what we wanted to kind of get across
today was a little bit about why we,
the class is structured the way it is.
What the different parts are.
And maybe go a little bit of back and
forth about what we think you should
be getting out of the course.
That seem reasonable?
&gt;&gt; Sure.
&gt;&gt; Okay.
Well, so,
first off, by the way, before we get
started, I wanted to thank you for
coming down to Atlanta, and
joining me in these beautiful, studios.
&gt;&gt; Well, it's, it's,
it's very nice to be here.
Thank you for inviting me.
&gt;&gt; Oh, no, no, thank you for
coming, Michael.
&gt;&gt; Thank you for
asking me to do the course.
This has been a lot of fun.
&gt;&gt; Oh, the whole point was to be able
to do the course with you, Michael.
We like each other, and that's one of
the things that we want you to get,
want to get across in this class,
because we like machine learning.
We've a lot of stuff in common, but I'm
not sure we completely agree on the most
important parts of machine learning and
why we do the things that we do.
&gt;&gt; Hm, all right.
&gt;&gt; So
I think people in the outside world,
Michael, would claim that you're
more theoretical than I am.
&gt;&gt; In theory.
&gt;&gt; In theory, and
I'm more practical than you are.
&gt;&gt; Practically.
&gt;&gt; At least in practice.
And hopefully some of that tension
will come out in the class.
But I think in order to see why
that tension works that way,
you have to understand
what machine learning is.
So, Michael.
&gt;&gt; Right.
&gt;&gt; What's machine learning?
&gt;&gt; It's about proving theorems.
&gt;&gt; [LAUGH] No.
&gt;&gt; No.
&gt;&gt; I would not say it's about proving
theorems, although proving theorems is
often important in machine learning.
&gt;&gt; I agree with that.
&gt;&gt; Okay.
&gt;&gt; So we're on the same page.
&gt;&gt; We're partially on the same page.
What is machine learning?
&gt;&gt; What is machine learning?
&gt;&gt; Give me a definition.
&gt;&gt; So it is computational statistics.
How's that for a definition?
&gt;&gt; That is a definition.
It is wrong on so many levels.
However, a lot of people would
agree with that statement.
They would say that machine learning
is really just applied statistics.
&gt;&gt; Not applied statistics.
Computational statistics.
&gt;&gt; Computationally applied statistics.
I don't like that definition.
I think that it's a bit too narrow.
I think that machine learning
is about this broader notion of
building artifacts,
computational artifacts, typically.
That learn over time
based on experience.
And then in particular,
it's not just the act
of building these artifacts that matter,
it's the math behind it.
It's the science behind it.
It's the engineering behind it,
and it's the computing behind it.
It's everything that goes into building
intelligent artifacts that almost by
necessity have to learn over time.
You buy that?
&gt;&gt; Yeah, so you, you have data, and
you do analysis of the data and
try to glean things from the data.
And you used, various kinds of
computational structure to do that,
so, computational statistics.
&gt;&gt; I don't think that's
computational statistics.